PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
In Pixar BOX
In Pixar BOX
Before looking at the function of the spline,
一会儿 我们会深入研究样条函数的数学原理
I'll show you the animation department in Pixarze.
但首先 我想带你们逛逛皮克斯动画部
We are constantly working on films,
尽管我们做的是电影
but the shoot does not exist.
但其实在动画电影中 一切场景都是模拟出来的
We work at the computer.
因此 我们的大部分工作 都是坐在电脑前完成的
It does not have to be boring.
但并不意味我们非得无聊地敲键盘
Because this work requires creativity,
既然从事的是极具创造性的工作
we try to Pixar creative favored.
那么打造一个让灵感迸发的活力工作间 就显得很重要
Animation department consists of several parts.
动画部门分成几个不同风格的“舱”
With various offices.
同一职务的人基本都在一个舱内工作
Each part has a different style.
每个舱都逐渐形成自己的风格
Here is a jungle. Lianas, leaves, lock ...
这儿是“丛林舱”  装饰着葡萄藤 城堡
The room itself resembles an airplane wreck.
是不是像在一架失事飞机的遗骸里
It is a meeting place for animators.
这儿是动画师们的中央聚集区
There is even a position to play live.
还有个可以现场演出的小舞台哦
In my spare time I am a DJ,
业余时间我会做做DJ
So in his office I put vinyl and adapter.
所以我把我的舱装饰成“黑胶休息室” 里面还有个唱片机哦
First, I will show you several methods used in the animation manually,
首先我要向大家展示手绘动画的基本技巧
and then to process it by computer.
然后再来讨论 在电脑中又是怎样操作的
We animate the ball using progressive redraw.
首先用“连续动作法”来绘制一个皮球弹起的动画
I'll start from the first frame.
我们先来画第一帧
I take a second card (thanks to the pins is equal).
然后在上面铺上一张动画纸 定位钉能让纸的边缘保持对齐
I draw the second frame.
在这里画第二帧
Now the third frame ...
然后是第三帧
And fourth.
还有第四帧
As you can see, I draw frames one, in order.
如你所见 我是一帧接一帧 顺着画下来的
When I'm done, wskanuję drawings and they can be played.
画完后 将这些画面扫描 连起来播放一下
Drawing progressive computer works the same way.
在电脑里也是一样
Tested in an interactive exercise.
你可以在下一节的交互性演示中试一下
Przeciągnijcie the ball where you want to be at the beginning of the animation,
把球拖到合适的起始位置
Move on to the next frame, and move over the ball.
然后移到第二帧 再把球拖到你想要的位置
In each frame a little further.
以此类推 每帧移动一点
Just do so in subsequent frames.
后面几帧也用同样的方式
When you're done, hit your "Play" to play the animation.
完成后按 play 键来查看你的动画
Let's see how you go!  aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
好了 来看看你能做到什么程度！ aimozhen.com/pixarinabox